Come .
Quiet .
... can be both a particle or a wave ,
depending on what kind of instrument we 're using .
- Hey , mom . - Hey .
- Is something wrong ? - No , I 'm home studying . Why ?
We 've been trying to call you .
I saw that , but I was in class .
What kind of class ?
Bio began today . I was going to call , but things got a bit hectic .
- Isn 't that in the morning ? - What do you mean ?
I thought it began at 8 . Biology is in the morning , right ?
Your dad showed me how we can follow your schedule online .
Yes , no ... They moved it to 6 for this week only .
But I 'm cooking food and ...
What are you making ?
- Just pasta and some stuff . - Alright .
- We can talk some other time . - Let 's talk tomorrow .
- Yes . - Yes .
- Ok . We love you . - I love you too .
- Bye then . - Bye .
Hello ?
Hello ? Hey !
Is somebody calling an ambulance ?
Did you go a long time without eating ?
No , not really .
Did you drink anything ?
Alcohol ?
- No , I 'm not really a drinker . - " Really " ?
- No , I don 't drink . - And you never experienced this before ?
No .
- Is it epilepsy ? - It 's too early to say .
Do you have a history with epilepsy in the family ?
- No , not that I know about . - I should look at your journal .
Can I call your previous doctor ?
Not really . I don 't want my parents to know about this .
They don 't have to know . I 'll just talk with your doctor .
Then you 'll decide if you want to tell them .
Alright . - 40 00 : 10 : 31,584 - - 00 : 10 : 36,834 - Is it anything serious ? - Not as far as we can tell .
But we 'll call you to run a few more tests in the future .
Try not to worry in the meantime .
- Hey . - Hey .
I wanted to say hello because I was present when
that thing happend . You had a ...
- Anyway , I 'm Anja . - Thelma .
- Are you feeling better ? - Yes , I 'm much better now .
That 's great .
- Are you attending chemistry too ? - No , biology .
That 's good .
- Perhaps I 'll see you in math . - Yes .
- Goodbye . - Goodbye .
- It 's in here . - ln here ?
That 's good .
- But when somebody talks about it , do you get ... - I don 't quite understand what you mean .
I remember Sofia and Gunnar 's dad .
- Aksel . - One time , when me and Sofia were attending a camp ,
begynte han å snakke om at fossiler stammer fra syndefloden og sånn .
Yes , you didn 't say much , but you finished a bit abruptly .
Marthe 's parents are like that too ...
We met Marthe at the mall . Was it last week ?
- She says hi . - That 's nice .
They are very nice people .
But they believe that life on earth began 6000 years ago .
I was visiting them , and there was this documentary ...
That 's enough , Thelma .
Don 't make fun of people .
I wasn 't . But don 't you agree that it 's a bit odd ?
I 'm not comfortable with this kind of talking .
- What do you mean ? - Knowledge don 't make us better than others .
How did life occur where there wasn 't any ?
Do you know why ?
No .
You talk like you know everything .
I don 't believe I am .
- Are you sad ? - Yes , a little .
Would you like to sit down ?
What is it ?
Sorry , dad .
I don 't know what 's going on with me .
Sometimes I think that I 'm better than others .
And I know that I 'm not , but it just happens .
I 'm glad you 're acknowledging it .
Is that all ?
When I see other girls with friends and boyfriends , I think they 're
uglier than me , says stupid things , and I don 't understand why they are ...
I see that there 's some new friends on your Facebook page .
What is it ?
I 'm talking to a few people before the lectures , but that 's all there is to it .
It seems like everyone but me knows someone already .
But they have to get to know you ..
You 're so great .
Thanks .
It just takes time .
We 'll call when we get home . Take care of yourself .
- See you soon . - Have a safe trip .
Hi ! So nice to see you . Are you leaving ... ?
No , I was supposed to meet someone , but they went elsewhere .
- Hi . - Julie .
Is it just coke ?
- Yes . - Just that ?
- Regular coke ? - Yes .
- Can I ask why ? - No , my family is Christian so it 's ...
- I grew up with it . - Is that true ?
Strictly Christian ? No . Ordinary Christian ?
That 's cool .
It 's exotic . I just ...
I think it 's strange that people believe .
- " Why is it like that ? " " Because God ... " - Or Santa Claus .
" Santa says that 's the way it is . Santa says contraception is wrong . "
" So we 'll just have 14 children . "
" Santa says you 're supposed to cover up . " I don 't understand it , it 's weird .
- You don 't believe in anything ? - No .
I believe in things that can be explained scientificly .
How do you explain how your phone works ?
- What do you mean by that ? - How does it work ?
- It 's not because someone says it 's working . - Well , there 's signals .
- What kind of signals ? - First of all , it 's not God .
I 'm sure about that . But signals as in ...
Help me out here ... It 's similar to radiation .
- " Radiation " ! - It is .
It 's radiation in the air , and you get cancer from it .
- Hi dad . - Hi .
Sorry for calling so late . My phone was in silent mode .
- Is everything OK ? - Yes .
Your mom gets so anxious when you don 't answer .
I know . Sorry .
She 's been thinking a lot lately , being in pain and such .
- Where are you ? Outside ? - Yes .
I 've been out with some friends . I 've had a lot of fun .
Yes .
It 's great that you 're having fun . Just be careful .
I am .
Okay . We 'll talk tomorrow .
I love you .
I love you too . Tell mom I 'm sorry ?
Yes , I 'll do that .
Okay . Goodnight then .
Goodnight . Bye .
Bye .
Hey .
Thelma ?
- Is there anyone you want to call ? - No , not now .
Sorry .
About what ? Don 't worry about it .
Are you tired ?
Yes .
Why were outside yesterday ?
Didn 't you text me ?
No , I don 't think so .
- No . - Did you know where I lived ?
I have to .
Yes , I 've probably told you .
I got pretty drunk yesterday . I barely remember anything .
... from the extreme value theorem , because ...
So a simple use of the theorem ...
I remember my dad holding my hand above the candle .
He removed it before it left any mark . But it hurt a lot .
Then he said ...
" That 's what Hell is like all the time . "
Are you kidding me ?
Are you ... Aren 't you mad at him ?
Well , it 's ...
It 's a long time ago .
He 's a nice guy .
Ok ?
He really is .
I can talk to him about anything .
- Do you talk to your dad about anything ? - Yes .
Is there anything wrong with that ?
No , but I think I 've talked to my dad about ...
Ten times .
Shit .
He doesn 't live in Norway . And he 's got lots of children .
I 'm not really sure if he likes kids .
Are you angry with him ?
I think I was for a while . But as I 'm getting older ,
there 's less need to involve him in my life ...
So I 'm fine with it .
" Jesus poop " ? That 's not quite right .
" Jesus pussy " .
The worst what ?
The worst thing you can say as a Christian .
Mixing the holy with the less holy .
" Jesus t _ "
- What did you just say ? - " Jesus fu ... " .
- Louder . - " Jesus fucker " .
- Why are you whispering ? - " Jesus fucker " !
There 's one there too .
It 's like that everywhere .
- A man ? - Yes .
World 's smallest man .
- It 's nice . - Thanks .
- Everything alright ? - I 'm not very experienced .
You don 't have to smoke . Let 's go inside .
- Thank you for letting me come . - You 're welcome .
It 's great of you to come .
It 's always nice meeting Anye 's friends . Have you been here before ?
No , I haven 't . It 's beautiful .
I think we 're supposed to go over here .
- Look . Have some to eat . - What 's that ?
It 's a food bar .
- I don 't want chocolate . - You haven 't eaten anything .
It 's ok . I don 't need to .
Why couldn 't Daniel come ?
- We broke up . - Shit ! What happend ?
Don 't tell mom . She loved him .
- Are you ok ? - I 'm fine .
Lord , take it away from me . Get rid of these thoughts . Take them ...
- Long day ? - Yes .
Are you able to get some rest when you get home ?
Yes .
Are you cooking food every day , or do you eat out ?
I 'm mostly cooking at home .
What have you been eating today ?
I made some vegetable soup .
Are you shopping down there ?
Yes .
What is it , Thelma ?
Nothing .
I can tell when there 's something wrong .
I ...
You can tell me anything . It 's important that you do .
I 've been drinking alcohol .
And I 'm very sorry .
How much ?
Two beers , with a couple of friends from the university .
Was that on the same day you didn 't call until late in the evening ?
Yes .
It 's probably alright .
You 're a grown up now . You have to experience things .
One beer doesn 't hurt .
Be careful not to lose touch with who you really are .
I know that .
- I 'm not . - Lot 's of people drink too much .
It 's easy to lose control .
Yes .
- I 'm really sorry . - It 's alright .
It 's alright , Thelma .
Don 't worry about it . I 'm glad you told me .
- Try to get some sleep . - Yes .
- Ok . Talk to you later . - Yes , we 'll do .
- Bye . - Bye .
The power that overcame death
lives on in those who believe in him .
The tomb is empty , Jesus lives
in honor and power .
Death is forever beneath him .
The tomb is empty , Jesus lives ...
Hello ! Come inside .
Hey .
There you go .
- Sorry , do you want something else ? - No , I 'm good .
Are you sure ? Cool !
- Hey . - Hey .
- You 're drinking ? - Yes .
Where have you been ? Did you not get my messages ?
I did , sorry . There 's been a lot going on lately . I forgot .
I 'm sorry I had to leave . Could you tell your mom I had a good time ?
I 'll do that .
- Are you ok ? - Yes , why ?
Did you arrive here with Kristoffer ?
Yes , we walked together .
Ok .
Hey !
I 'm not having any .
- There 's lots of people here not smoking . - She knows that .
I 'm leaving .
Inhale it into your lungs .
Oh , shit .
- Do you feel anything ? - Perhaps a little bit .
That 's good . What ?
One more time .
Now I feel something .
- Yeah ? - You 're wasted .
Is this common ?
Yes .
Hey ! Hello ?
I 'm just messing with you . There 's no weed , only tobacco .
Get it ? They 're idiots .
- Yes , they were joking . - Yes , we messed around .
- It got out of hand . - Did you think that was cool ?
No , it wasn 't cool , but ...
Oh , shit .
- Are you alright ? - Sorry .
The scan we just did rule out brain tumor .
I 'll be sending you to an epilepsy clinic .
We 'll have to measure your brain activity during a sizure in order to diagnose you .
- Why ? - They 've got room for you .
They 're able to monitor you over a longer period of time .
I 'm sitting here with your journal .
It says you had a seizure when you were six years old .
It was diagnosed as a nervous breakdown .
Are you sure about that ?
It says that you were put on antipsychotics afterwards
for irregular sleep – wake rhythm .
- I didn 't know that . - They gave you Nozinan .
Nozinan is a very powerful drug for a child .
Yes .
Apart from that , there 's very little here . Almost nothing .
My dad is a doctor , so he always took care of things .
- You 're dad is a doctor ? - Yeah , a general practitioner .
You should ask him about this then .
- He 'll probably be able to explain it to you . - Ok .
Mom ?
Yes .
Not right now , Thelma . Can 't you see that he 's eating ?
You !
Go downstairs and draw something , ok ?
There you go .
Mattias ?
Mattias !
Where 's Mattias ?
Did you take him ? Don 't do that . Where did you put him ?
- I don 't know . - Tell me where you put him .
Tell me where you put him , Thelma !
Thelma , where did you put him ?
Quiet . Trond !
Trond ! He 's here !
Be careful . Yes .
One more time . Could you open your eyes ?
Breathe in and out .
Good !
Could you close your eyes ?
Open up your eyes , then breathe a bit faster .
Breathe in . Notice how you 're filling up your lungs .
Keep it in . And breathe .
Good .
We 're ready to begin .
To provoke a seizure , we have to
go to some rather unpleasant places .
If it gets too uncomfortable , just say so .
Ok .
How are you now , leading up to the exams ? Are you stressed ?
Yes , quite so .
It 's alright for you to answer . You may also nod or shake your head .
Think about the things I 'm asking you , and let the thoughts come to you .
You said you had a breakdown as a child .
When you were six .
Do you remember any of it ?
Do you remember anything about your parents from back then ?
- It must have been difficult for you . - Yes . No , I don 't remember much .
You moved to the city not long ago .
Have you gotten any friends ?
What about boys ?
If this is painful , try not to block it .
Is there someone in particular ?
Perhaps it 's not a boy ? Close your eyes .
Breathe a bit faster .
Faster . Good .
Breathe even faster .
Hello ?
Open your eyes . Watch the light .
Breathe faster . That 's good .
I can tell you 're thinking about something painfull . Don 't ignore it . Reach into it .
Go deeper .
Breathe faster . Breathe in and out .
Lord , take it away from me . Get rid of these thoughts . Take it away from me .
Hey , it 's Anja . Please leave a message .
I 'm forwarding a bit here .
Watch this . Nothing happens .
If it was epilepsy , there would 've been a significant change .
So it 's not epilepsy ?
No , it 's not .
What is it then ? What is happening to me ?
It fits with so-called non-epileptic seizures .
Ok ?
These seizures could be the result of something else .
The body reacts to something being repressed .
- I don 't understand . - It could be because of stress .
It could be some sort of trauma .
Lots of different things .
But I 've been looking a bit at the genetic systems .
Your grandma had a history of mental health problems .
- Are you saing that I 'm mentally ill ? - Not at all .
- Am I crazy , like grandma ? - No ...
Calm down . I 'm not sure what she suffered from .
But she was admitted for a long period of time .
You probably know more about that than I do .
No , I don 't . She died a long time ago .
That 's strange .
It says here that ...
She was admitted to Hellersmo in 2016 .
The point is that further examinations were done by a psychiatrist .
- That can 't be right . - It is .
It says here that she was admitted to Hellersmo during the spring in 2016 .
That 's the latest one .
A psychiatrist will examine you from now on .
You 'll be able to discuss these things in further detail .
Psychological non-epileptic seizures is a very misunderstood disorder .
She 's having a grand mal .
For 3,000 years , people believed it was something supernatural . That you were being invaded
or posessed by witches who punished the sick .
The word " seizure " means being posessed by external powers ,
either gods or demons , depending on what century they were living in .
Hello ?
Grandma ?
It 's Thelma .
Trond 's daughter .
Hey , it 's Thelma .
She 's been like this for years . I don 't think she knows we 're here .
She used to be more lucent , but then the delusions were stronger .
I think the medications she 's on is too strong .
What kind of delusions ?
She took it pretty hard when her husband disappeared .
- What happend ? - They never found his body , only the boat .
She thought it was somehow her fault .
She was awfully confused .
When she got cancer , she thought she had given it to her herself .
- What do you mean ? - Well , she meant ...
That she made things happen .
I told your dad the last time he came by that the drugs were too strong .
He didn 't seem too concerned .
Hei , it 's Anja . Please leave a message .
... pretty clear . Apply the algebra for n-tuples to all values of n .
But then there 's these two and three-dimensional interpretations ...
Something happend . I had a seizure . I don 't know what 's going on . A girl ...
What ? What 's going on ?
A girl has disappeared .
And I know that it 's my fault .
I can 't stop thinking about it . I know it 's my fault .
Can I come home ?
Of course you can , sweetheart .
Ok .
I know that it 's been costing you a lot of money for me not having to work during my studies .
- I 'm sorry it turned out this way . - You can graduate another time .
Don 't worry about it .
What 's wrong with you then ?
I 've been having these seizures , epileptic seizures .
- But it 's something else . - Psychological seizures ?
Yes .
I had a patient who were diagnosed with that a few years ago .
- Ok ? - It turned out fine .
Drink your tea . Don 't worry about it .
The doctors says it could be stress , but I don 't know . I don 't really understand .
Are you alright ?
Yes .
I 'm just tired .
Don 't be scared . We gave you something to calm you down .
We know what 's happening to you , Thelma . We 'll help you .
I have to tell you something .
It 's gonna hurt a lot .
" Quack , quack . " Mom forgot the rag , and you have to behave .
I 'll be right back . Could you watch this for me ? Good !
Already up ? Just go back to bed .
Trond ! Trond ?
Mattias !
Trond !
Where is he ?
Did you do anything ? Say it .
- Tell me if you did anything . - I didn 't .
I can 't find him !
Is he down there ?
He 's not up here either .
Why aren 't you answering ?
No ! No !
No !
There 'something in you . If you want something , if you really want something ,
what you 're thinking , feeling , something in you makes it happen .
- Do you understand what I 'm saying ? - Yes .
Are you awake ?
Are you able to get up ?
Open up .
Lift your tongue .
I 'm sorry . I shouldn 't have let you go .
I thought it was over . Nothing has happend since you met God when you were little .
I 'll help you .
Holy God , have mercy on me who 's offended you
with evil thoughts and actions . Give me a clean heart , strength for a new life .
Give me a clean heart , strength for a new life .
Holy God , have mercy on me who 's offended you
with evil thoughts and actions . Give me ...
I 'm angry .
I 'm angry with you , God .
Why are you doing this to me ?
What do you want ?
I 'm angry with dad too .
I 'm not worth it . He 's got to stop . I can 't handle it anymore .
Why can 't I just be myself ? Why isn 't that possible ?
What about the poor girl ?
Who disappeared .
Were you angry with her too ?
No .
I was in love with her .
And she was in love with me .
She didn 't love you , Thelma .
Think about it .
Did she like you before you wanted her ?
Do you think she had a choice considering what 's inside you ?
You were probably just lonely .
You needed someone .
- I didn 't want her to disappear . - You wanted it in your innermost thoughts .
It happends .
- Goodnight . - Goodnight .
This isn 't working .
We can 't sit here and kid ourselves .
What if she does it again ?
You 'll never be able to forgive yourself .
You ...
You 're a good man . You 're so kind .
But this is about something much bigger than the two of us .
We 're being tested .
You said that if this doesn 't work out ,
we 'll have to face the consequences .
No matter how painful it is .
Or how much we love her .
You 've done everything you can .
And we 'll all be united again .
- Hey , Trond . - Hey .
Is that Thelma ?
- Is she visiting ? - No , Thelma moved back home .
That 's good .
It 's alright . I 'll take care of it .
I went to see grandma at the hospital .
Are you doing the same thing to me ?
Is it ?
Could you please let me go ?
Get some sleep .
Trond ?
Trond !
Where 's Trond ?
What 's happening ?
Thelma , don 't go . Thelma !
Thelma !
Thelma ! Thelma ...
- Hey . - Hey .
- You look like a real babe today . - Thank you .
You too . You look nice in my jacket .
Tekster : Erik Grønvold